<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TableTop on granthutchison</title>
    
    
    
    <link>/categories/tabletop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TableTop on granthutchison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>©2019 - 2022 Grant Hutchison: CC BY-SA 4.0 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 16:36:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/tabletop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentinels of the Multiverse Review</title>
      <link>/posts/sentinels-of-the-multiverse-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 16:36:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sentinels-of-the-multiverse-review/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-10/sentinels-header.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          Sentinels of the Multiverse Review # (This review was originally posted on Boardgaming.com and subsequently posted on the old version of this blog, hence the 2015 post date!)
Sentinels, ASSEMBLE # Baron Blade and his minions are attempting to destroy Megalopolis using their mobile attack platform! It’s time to join forces with Legacy and the other heroes of the Multiverse to take him down!
Sentinels of the Multiverse is a co-operative card game for 2-5 players, which can be played in 30-45 minutes (although you might just find you want to start another game straight after…)
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battlestar Galactica: The Board Game Review</title>
      <link>/posts/battlestar_galactica_the_board_game_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 14:10:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/battlestar_galactica_the_board_game_review/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-10/bsg01_feature.jpeg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          BattleStar Galactica: The Board Game - Review # (This review was originally posted on Boardgaming.com and subsequently posted on the old version of this blog)
Humanity has lost # The second Cylon war is over. Humanity has lost, and now it’s only hope for survival is a small fleet of ships carrying all that remains of the human population, lead by the aging Battlestar Galactica.
Battlestar Galactica: The Board Game is based on the first season of the 2004 re-imagining of the classic 70’s TV show, where the surviving human fleet desperately tries to escape their Cylon pursuers on their way to the planet Kobol – the legendary planet where humanity began (and a waypoint on their longer journey to find the fabled 13th colony, Earth).
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>