<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on granthutchison</title>
    <link>/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on granthutchison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>©2019 - 2020 Grant Hutchison: CC BY-SA 4.0 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:46:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebound MTB App</title>
      <link>/posts/rebound-mtb-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:46:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rebound-mtb-app/</guid>
      <description>The Rebound MTB App Part 1: The beta release For the past forever I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying with the Open University, working towards a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Software Engineering and after all that time the end is in sight!.
To complete the degree I have to undertake a significant project, so I&amp;rsquo;ve teamed up with the guys at Rebound to build a mobile application to support them.
Rebound is a registered charity, which aims to &amp;ldquo;develop the local community through sport&amp;rdquo; - with a primary focus on mountain biking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Things to Do While Your Electric Car Charges</title>
      <link>/posts/5-things-to-do-while-your-electric-car-charges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 16:51:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/5-things-to-do-while-your-electric-car-charges/</guid>
      <description>7 Things to do while your electric car charges So after writing a bit about how long an electric car takes to charge, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a short post about things to do to whilst your car charges - believe it or not this is something I Googled while I was first investigating EV ownership!
1. Write a blog post There&amp;rsquo;s something quite therapeutic about writing, even when you&amp;rsquo;re not very good at it&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Long Does an EV Take to Charge</title>
      <link>/posts/how-long-does-an-ev-take-to-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 01:39:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-long-does-an-ev-take-to-charge/</guid>
      <description>How long does an electric car take to charge? After &amp;ldquo;How far does it go?&amp;rdquo;, the next most common question I&amp;rsquo;ve heard since buying an electric car is &amp;ldquo;How long does it take to charge?&amp;rdquo;.
I think a lot of people find the answer surprising, I certainly did when I started investigating purchasing a hybrid and quickly found myself drawn towards the mysterious world of EV ownership.
The answer though is &amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, quickly followed by &amp;ldquo;and that&amp;rsquo;s not really the right question anyway&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>