<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Release Notes on granthutchison</title>
    <link>/tags/release-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Release Notes on granthutchison</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 15:44:33 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/release-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WristCheck v1.5 Release Notes</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck_v1.5_release_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 15:44:33 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck_v1.5_release_notes/</guid>
      <description>WristCheck v1.5 Release Notes Opps - I seem to have skipped writing up notes when I released WristCheck v1.4! (and for the last couple of Air Fryr releases&amp;hellip;) I&amp;rsquo;ll add a quick summary at the end!&#xA;But onto the details - WristCheck 1.5 is a fairly big update to the user interface of the main watchbox view. I&amp;rsquo;ve made search more prominent, given a use the ability to re-order the watch display, included images on the main page (so that you can find the watch you&amp;rsquo;re looking for visually) and made it easier to jump between the various watch box views (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Fryr</title>
      <link>/posts/air_fryr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 09:41:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/air_fryr/</guid>
      <description>Air Fryr - An Air Fryer Companion app With energy bills going through the roof, the world seems to have gone air fryer mad over the last year or so.&#xA;I had an old one that was only ever used for making chips (aka French fries for any readers on the other side of the Atlantic!), but I recently had a bunch of cashback pending from Quidco (if you&amp;rsquo;re in the UK and don&amp;rsquo;t already use Quidco you should give them a look), so decided to treat myself to an absolute beast of an Air Fryer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New App: MP Checklist</title>
      <link>/posts/new_app_mp_checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 13:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/new_app_mp_checklist/</guid>
      <description>A helper app for Metroid Prime&amp;hellip; Ok, so I realise this post quickly became an essay - if you want to read some background please read on, but if you just want to know about the app, please feel free to skip to the end.&#xA;Returning to Tallon VI From 2002 until early 2017 if anyone asked me what my favourite game of all time was (and I know that&amp;rsquo;s a school playground question&amp;hellip;) without hesitation I&amp;rsquo;d have answered Metroid Prime.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WristCheck v1.3 Release Notes</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck_v1.3_release_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 15:44:33 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck_v1.3_release_notes/</guid>
      <description>WristCheck v1.3 Release Notes Version 1.3 of WristCheck is now available to the app beta testers, so will be released over the next couple of days (as I write this I&amp;rsquo;ve already got confirmation that Apple have approved it, so it&amp;rsquo;s just a case of hitting the button!) As before I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a post with a bit more information on what&amp;rsquo;s changed, expanding a bit on the bullet points you&amp;rsquo;ll see in the app or on the store listings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wristcheck v1.2</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck_v1.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 10:32:34 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck_v1.2/</guid>
      <description>WristCheck v1.2 is live! So, fairly hot on the heels of my last post, there&amp;rsquo;s another update to WristCheck landing in the app stores imminently (as I write it&amp;rsquo;s already live on Android, and should hit iOS early next week).&#xA;So, what&amp;rsquo;s new this time?&#xA;Ads! Yep, I originally said these would be in v1.1, but I wanted to make sure backup/restore and notifications could be properly tested, so I pushed out v1.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
