<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on granthutchison</title>
    
    
    
    <link>/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on granthutchison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>©2019 - 2022 Grant Hutchison: CC BY-SA 4.0 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 19:25:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MP Checklist Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/mp_checklist_privacy_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 19:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/mp_checklist_privacy_policy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          MP Checklist Privacy Policy v1.0 # Privacy Policy
Grant Hutchison built the MP Checklist app as an Ad Supported app. This SERVICE is provided by Grant Hutchison at no cost and is intended for use as is.
This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.
If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WristCheck v1.3 Release Notes</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck_v1.3_release_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 15:44:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck_v1.3_release_notes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-10/WristCheck_PickImg_code.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          WristCheck v1.3 Release Notes # Version 1.3 of WristCheck is now available to the app beta testers, so will be released over the next couple of days (as I write this I&amp;rsquo;ve already got confirmation that Apple have approved it, so it&amp;rsquo;s just a case of hitting the button!) As before I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a post with a bit more information on what&amp;rsquo;s changed, expanding a bit on the bullet points you&amp;rsquo;ll see in the app or on the store listings.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wristcheck 101: A guide for new users</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck_101_a_guide_for_new_users/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 18:57:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck_101_a_guide_for_new_users/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-10/wristcheck_101/confused-bearded-guy-shrugging-can-t-understand-how-use-mobile-phone-app.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          WristCheck 101: Getting started with WristCheck # WristCheck has been out in the wild for a little over a month now, and as I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before I&amp;rsquo;ve got plans to continually add more functionality to the app and keep it supported for a good while (free time permitting of course!)
Now I&amp;rsquo;d not claim to be the worlds best developer, nor am I a professional UX designer - I&amp;rsquo;ve just built an app to the best of my abilities that performs some functions that I want access to (and on the way added some things based on user feedback) - so the app has a few bugs and might not be as straight-forward to navigate as I think it is&amp;hellip;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wristcheck v1.2</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck_v1.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 10:32:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck_v1.2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-10/reminder.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          WristCheck v1.2 is live! # So, fairly hot on the heels of my last post, there&amp;rsquo;s another update to WristCheck landing in the app stores imminently (as I write it&amp;rsquo;s already live on Android, and should hit iOS early next week).
So, what&amp;rsquo;s new this time?
Ads! # Yep, I originally said these would be in v1.1, but I wanted to make sure backup/restore and notifications could be properly tested, so I pushed out v1.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wristcheck v1.1 Preview</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck_1.1_preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 09:39:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck_1.1_preview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-09/Curtains.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          WristCheck v1.1 Preview # If you are not embarrassed by the first version of your product, you’ve launched too late. - Reid Hoffman, LinkedIn founder
I love the above quote, and when I hit release on WristCheck v1.0 I was acutely aware that this app was not finished!
I&amp;rsquo;ve got a whole bunch of additional features I&amp;rsquo;m planning to add, but initially I&amp;rsquo;ve set my sights on a small number that will make up v1.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wristcheck Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/wristcheck_privacy_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 13:11:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/wristcheck_privacy_policy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          WristCheck Privacy Policy v1.0.0 # Grant Hutchison built the WristCheck app as an Ad Supported app. This SERVICE is provided by Grant Hutchison at no cost and is intended for use as is.
This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.
If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wristcheck App</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:31:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-09/WristCheckCover.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          WristCheck App # Version 1.0.0 is live! # I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve just released my first fully released app on both Android and iOS! (If you&amp;rsquo;re browsing around you may see I have previously posted about the ReboundMTB app, however this was never fully released!).
What is WristCheck? # WristCheck is a digital watch box, so if you&amp;rsquo;re both a) a watch collector, and b) a nerd, then this post might interest you!
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebound MTB App</title>
      <link>/posts/rebound-mtb-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:46:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rebound-mtb-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2020-07/ReboundMTB.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          The Rebound MTB App # Part 1: The beta release # For the past forever I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying with the Open University, working towards a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Software Engineering and after all that time the end is in sight!.
To complete the degree I have to undertake a significant project, so I&amp;rsquo;ve teamed up with the guys at Rebound to build a mobile application to support them.
Rebound is a registered charity, which aims to &amp;ldquo;develop the local community through sport&amp;rdquo; - with a primary focus on mountain biking.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebound App Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/app-privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:27:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/app-privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post contains the Privacy Policy generated for the Rebound MTB app, developed in collaboration with Rebound SCIO
Privacy Policy
Rebound SCIO built the Rebound MTB app as an Open Source app. This SERVICE is provided by Rebound SCIO at no cost and is intended for use as is.
This page is used to inform visitors regarding our policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use our Service.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Workflow</title>
      <link>/posts/blog-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 16:31:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blog-workflow/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-11/blogging.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          My blog workflow # So, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post as much for my own benefit as anyone else&amp;rsquo;s. The last time I tried to build a blog I left it alone for a while and when I came back to it I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten the steps to build it&amp;hellip; If this is of benefit to anyone else though, great!
I&amp;rsquo;ve put this blog together using Hugo, a static site generator. What does that mean?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>