<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>granthutchison</title>
    
    
    
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on granthutchison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>©2019 - 2022 Grant Hutchison: CC BY-SA 4.0 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:06:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Addings Ads</title>
      <link>/posts/addings_ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:06:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/addings_ads/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-09/DigitalScreens_TimesSquareSpectacular.jpeg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          Adding Ads&amp;hellip; and stuff&amp;hellip; # Yep, I&amp;rsquo;ve done it&amp;hellip;sorry.
I&amp;rsquo;ve gone ahead and added some hideous advertising all across the site&amp;hellip;but why?
Good question, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I have a good answer&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s not really to make money, as the volume of readers of this site are tiny. It&amp;rsquo;s a site I&amp;rsquo;ve built far more for myself than for anyone else, but hey, if you&amp;rsquo;ve found you&amp;rsquo;re way here thanks for visiting (and if you&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed your time here, even better!
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>granthutchison.com Cookie Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/website-cookie-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/website-cookie-policy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Cookie Policy for granthutchison.com # This is the Cookie Policy for granthutchison.com, accessible from granthutchison.com
What Are Cookies # As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or &amp;lsquo;break&amp;rsquo; certain elements of the sites functionality.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>granthutchison.com Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/website_privacy_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/website_privacy_policy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Summary: This is a template generated privacy policy, but to summarise, on the site I have implemented Google Analytics to understand site usage, as well as Google Adsense to allow me to generate a tiny income to go towards domain costs. I don&amp;rsquo;t track any user information, but cookies from these services do. I encourage you to also review the privacy policies associated with these services.
Privacy Policy of granthutchison.com # Grant Hutchison operates the granthutchison.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Scrum Master // Developer // GeekDad # Hi, my name is Grant and I created this place so that I had somewhere to dump my thoughts and share my projects on the internet.
By day I&amp;rsquo;m a Scrum Master at a large UK bank, helping to transform our business and digital delivery to be more Agile.
I love the work that I do and the people that I do it with - as with many who work with Agile methodologies I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about working smarter to deliver better outcomes faster for our users and stakeholders.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wristcheck Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/wristcheck_privacy_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 13:11:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/wristcheck_privacy_policy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          WristCheck Privacy Policy v1.0.0 # Grant Hutchison built the WristCheck app as an Ad Supported app. This SERVICE is provided by Grant Hutchison at no cost and is intended for use as is.
This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.
If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wristcheck App</title>
      <link>/posts/wristcheck-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:31:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wristcheck-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2022-09/WristCheckCover.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          WristCheck App # Version 1.0.0 is live! # I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve just released my first fully released app on both Android and iOS! (If you&amp;rsquo;re browsing around you may see I have previously posted about the ReboundMTB app, however this was never fully released!).
What is WristCheck? # WristCheck is a digital watch box, so if you&amp;rsquo;re both a) a watch collector, and b) a nerd, then this post might interest you!
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebound MTB App</title>
      <link>/posts/rebound-mtb-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:46:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rebound-mtb-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2020-07/ReboundMTB.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          The Rebound MTB App # Part 1: The beta release # For the past forever I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying with the Open University, working towards a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Software Engineering and after all that time the end is in sight!.
To complete the degree I have to undertake a significant project, so I&amp;rsquo;ve teamed up with the guys at Rebound to build a mobile application to support them.
Rebound is a registered charity, which aims to &amp;ldquo;develop the local community through sport&amp;rdquo; - with a primary focus on mountain biking.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muc-Off Tubeless Valves Review</title>
      <link>/posts/muc-off-tubless-valves-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 01:09:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/muc-off-tubless-valves-review/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2020-07/muc-off-pack-cover.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          MTB Lockdown upgrades part 2: Muc-Off Tubeless Valves Review # My lockdown quest to add more shiny, orange bits to my main mountain bike continues! This time, I&amp;rsquo;m adding a little more bling, but with arguably a bit more functional value thrown in compared to the Wolf Tooth Blink Kit that I reviewed in my first #LockdownUpgrades post.
Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you, Muc-Off Tubeless Valves:
Valves: Muc-Off; Fingers: Models own What do they do?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolf Tooth Bling Kit Review</title>
      <link>/posts/wolf-tooth-bling-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 01:30:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wolf-tooth-bling-kit/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2020-06/WT_Bling_Kit_official.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          MTB Lockdown upgrades part 1: The Wolf Tooth Bling Kit # Like many parts of the world, the global Covid-19 pandemic has lead to a period of lockdown in Scotland, which has resulted in me transitioning to working from home, whilst also home-schooling my kids and unable to get out properly on my mountain bike (I say &amp;lsquo;properly&amp;rsquo; as I have no decent trails near me - I am however getting out whenever I can just to spin the wheels with my boys, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been entirely unable to send it).
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebound App Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/app-privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:27:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/app-privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          This post contains the Privacy Policy generated for the Rebound MTB app, developed in collaboration with Rebound SCIO
Privacy Policy
Rebound SCIO built the Rebound MTB app as an Open Source app. This SERVICE is provided by Rebound SCIO at no cost and is intended for use as is.
This page is used to inform visitors regarding our policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use our Service.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Things to Do While Your Electric Car Charges</title>
      <link>/posts/5-things-to-do-while-your-electric-car-charges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 16:51:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/5-things-to-do-while-your-electric-car-charges/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-11/coffee&amp;games.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          7 Things to do while your electric car charges # So after writing a bit about how long an electric car takes to charge, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a short post about things to do to whilst your car charges - believe it or not this is something I Googled while I was first investigating EV ownership!
1. Write a blog post # There&amp;rsquo;s something quite therapeutic about writing, even when you&amp;rsquo;re not very good at it&amp;hellip;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Long Does an EV Take to Charge</title>
      <link>/posts/how-long-does-an-ev-take-to-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 01:39:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-long-does-an-ev-take-to-charge/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-09/Fuelguage.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          How long does an electric car take to charge? # After &amp;ldquo;How far does it go?&amp;rdquo;, the next most common question I&amp;rsquo;ve heard since buying an electric car is &amp;ldquo;How long does it take to charge?&amp;rdquo;.
I think a lot of people find the answer surprising, I certainly did when I started investigating purchasing a hybrid and quickly found myself drawn towards the mysterious world of EV ownership.
The answer though is &amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, quickly followed by &amp;ldquo;and that&amp;rsquo;s not really the right question anyway&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Workflow</title>
      <link>/posts/blog-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 16:31:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blog-workflow/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-11/blogging.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          My blog workflow # So, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post as much for my own benefit as anyone else&amp;rsquo;s. The last time I tried to build a blog I left it alone for a while and when I came back to it I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten the steps to build it&amp;hellip; If this is of benefit to anyone else though, great!
I&amp;rsquo;ve put this blog together using Hugo, a static site generator. What does that mean?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cart Before Horse</title>
      <link>/posts/cart-before-the-horse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 12:12:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cart-before-the-horse/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Putting the Cart before the Horse # So, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the first website I&amp;rsquo;ve ever thrown together. Nor the first blog. Not even the first blog built using a static site generator&amp;hellip;
A few years ago (I&amp;rsquo;d love to say a couple, but I&amp;rsquo;m scared it&amp;rsquo;s now far more&amp;hellip;), I registered the domain granthutchison.com, not only because vanity domains are cool, but because I wanted to carve out a little corner of the internet to write and play.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>