<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on granthutchison.com</title>
    <link>granthutchison.com/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on granthutchison.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 17:16:39 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="granthutchison.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Even</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/breaking_even/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 17:16:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/breaking_even/</guid>
      <description>Breaking Even&amp;hellip; Right, while I&amp;rsquo;m in the blogging mood, here&amp;rsquo;s another post that really is long overdue! Back in March (wow!) I wrote a quick update on how much income I&amp;rsquo;d made via advertising on WristCheck and via ads on the website and promised further updates.&#xA;Since then a few major things have happened - firstly, I released two additional apps (technically I released MP Checklist just before that post&amp;hellip;) and secondly I finally got around to adding an in-app payment option to allow users to pay what they wanted to turn the ads off forever (and again, I definitely need to write a little about how and why I implemented that!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Millionaire Life</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/the_millionaire_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 14:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/the_millionaire_life/</guid>
      <description>Users and Earnings So, back in September I both implemented ads on the site and released my first proper app (although I didn&amp;rsquo;t put Ads into WristCheck until v1.2 about a month later).&#xA;This was all a fun experiment to see if I could make this wee hobby break even&amp;hellip; want to hear how it&amp;rsquo;s going?&#xA;A summary of costs Let&amp;rsquo;s start off with what it costs to put things together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addings Ads</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/addings_ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:06:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/addings_ads/</guid>
      <description>Adding Ads&amp;hellip; and stuff&amp;hellip; Yep, I&amp;rsquo;ve done it&amp;hellip;sorry.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve gone ahead and added some hideous advertising all across the site&amp;hellip;but why?&#xA;Good question, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I have a good answer&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s not really to make money, as the volume of readers of this site are tiny. It&amp;rsquo;s a site I&amp;rsquo;ve built far more for myself than for anyone else, but hey, if you&amp;rsquo;ve found you&amp;rsquo;re way here thanks for visiting (and if you&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed your time here, even better!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
