<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on granthutchison.com</title>
    <link>granthutchison.com/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on granthutchison.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 17:45:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="granthutchison.com/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zombie Dice Review</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/zombie-dice-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 17:45:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/zombie-dice-review/</guid>
      <description>Brains is good food&amp;hellip; (Like some of my other tabletop reviews this was originally posted on Boardgaming.com almost a decade ago! I&amp;rsquo;m reposting here as I liked writing these and might well add a few more if there&amp;rsquo;s interest) When there is no more room in hell, the dead shall walk the earth… and try to eat your brain, unless you can run away or blast them with a shotgun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muc-Off Tubeless Valves Review</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/muc-off-tubless-valves-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 01:09:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/muc-off-tubless-valves-review/</guid>
      <description>MTB Lockdown upgrades part 2: Muc-Off Tubeless Valves Review My lockdown quest to add more shiny, orange bits to my main mountain bike continues! This time, I&amp;rsquo;m adding a little more bling, but with arguably a bit more functional value thrown in compared to the Wolf Tooth Blink Kit that I reviewed in my first #LockdownUpgrades post.&#xA;Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you, Muc-Off Tubeless Valves:&#xA;Valves: Muc-Off; Fingers: Models own What do they do?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wolf Tooth Bling Kit Review</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/wolf-tooth-bling-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 01:30:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/wolf-tooth-bling-kit/</guid>
      <description>MTB Lockdown upgrades part 1: The Wolf Tooth Bling Kit Like many parts of the world, the global Covid-19 pandemic has lead to a period of lockdown in Scotland, which has resulted in me transitioning to working from home, whilst also home-schooling my kids and unable to get out properly on my mountain bike (I say &amp;lsquo;properly&amp;rsquo; as I have no decent trails near me - I am however getting out whenever I can just to spin the wheels with my boys, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been entirely unable to send it).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentinels of the Multiverse Review</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/sentinels-of-the-multiverse-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 16:36:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/sentinels-of-the-multiverse-review/</guid>
      <description>Sentinels of the Multiverse Review (This review was originally posted on Boardgaming.com and subsequently posted on the old version of this blog, hence the 2015 post date!)&#xA;Sentinels, ASSEMBLE Baron Blade and his minions are attempting to destroy Megalopolis using their mobile attack platform! It’s time to join forces with Legacy and the other heroes of the Multiverse to take him down!&#xA;Sentinels of the Multiverse is a co-operative card game for 2-5 players, which can be played in 30-45 minutes (although you might just find you want to start another game straight after…)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Settlers of Catan Review</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/settlers-of-catan-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 16:13:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/settlers-of-catan-review/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Catan! (Like some of my other tabletop reviews this was originally posted on Boardgaming.com almost a decade ago! I&amp;rsquo;m reposting here as I liked writing these and might well add a few more if there&amp;rsquo;s interest)&#xA;As one of a handful of new settlers on this newly colonised island, your goal is to build and expand, using your resources to become the dominant individual on the island.&#xA;Like many others who have written reviews of this great game, Catan was what I consider to be my first ‘real’ introduction to the wonderful world of board gaming, so it felt right that it should also be one of the first reviews I posted on the site!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battlestar Galactica: The Board Game Review</title>
      <link>granthutchison.com/posts/battlestar_galactica_the_board_game_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 14:10:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>granthutchison.com/posts/battlestar_galactica_the_board_game_review/</guid>
      <description>BattleStar Galactica: The Board Game - Review (This review was originally posted on Boardgaming.com and subsequently posted on the old version of this blog)&#xA;Humanity has lost The second Cylon war is over. Humanity has lost, and now it’s only hope for survival is a small fleet of ships carrying all that remains of the human population, lead by the aging Battlestar Galactica.&#xA;Battlestar Galactica: The Board Game is based on the first season of the 2004 re-imagining of the classic 70’s TV show, where the surviving human fleet desperately tries to escape their Cylon pursuers on their way to the planet Kobol – the legendary planet where humanity began (and a waypoint on their longer journey to find the fabled 13th colony, Earth).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
